<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Windows on MegaSmidge</title>
    <link>https://megasmidge.com/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Windows on MegaSmidge</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 19:29:11 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://megasmidge.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>I Finally Tried PopOS</title>
      <link>https://megasmidge.com/posts/i-finally-tried-popos/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 19:29:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://megasmidge.com/posts/i-finally-tried-popos/</guid>
      <description>I bit the bullet and installed Fedora on my tower. I mirrored everything I did on the XPS-15, including the setup for DBD, and it ran just terribly. It has something to do with the Nvidia drivers not playing well with Fedora. The GPU is an RTX 2060, but that&amp;rsquo;s way better than an integrated graphics driver on a laptop, or so I thought. Launching DBD took forever. I tried several YouTube videos and tutorials explaining how to install the drivers on Fedora, but each attempt ended worse than the one before it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Remote Gameplay Sucks</title>
      <link>https://megasmidge.com/posts/remote-gameplay-sucks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 22:25:16 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://megasmidge.com/posts/remote-gameplay-sucks/</guid>
      <description>Well I had a plan, but things didn&amp;rsquo;t go quite how I expected. RDP was just way too rough to play Dead By Daylight. Luckily, Steam made a tool called Steam Link that you can install on a linux machine or mobile device. It allows you to run the games from your main computer, and see the games on your remote computer. You send your keyboard/mouse from the remote computer to the main computer to play the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting Windows Aside</title>
      <link>https://megasmidge.com/posts/setting-windows-aside/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 19:31:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://megasmidge.com/posts/setting-windows-aside/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Windows user most of my 34 years on this earth. It was a matter of what my parents had in the house growing up in the 90s. As someone who got into videogames at a young age, Windows was the only way to go at the time. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t interested in building anything or being super technical, and it never even crossed my mind that I could be &amp;ldquo;good at computers&amp;rdquo; to pay the bills.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
