<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on MegaSmidge</title>
        <link>https://megasmidge.com/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on MegaSmidge</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en-us</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 19:29:11 -0800</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://megasmidge.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>I Finally Tried PopOS</title>
            <link>https://megasmidge.com/posts/i-finally-tried-popos/</link>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 19:29:11 -0800</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://megasmidge.com/posts/i-finally-tried-popos/</guid>
            <description>I bit the bullet and installed Fedora on my tower. I mirrored everything I did on the XPS-15, including the setup for DBD, and it ran just terribly. It has something to do with the Nvidia drivers not playing well with Fedora. The GPU is an RTX 2060, but that&amp;rsquo;s way better than an integrated graphics driver on a laptop, or so I thought. Launching DBD took forever. I tried several YouTube videos and tutorials explaining how to install the drivers on Fedora, but each attempt ended worse than the one before it.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I bit the bullet and installed Fedora on my tower. I mirrored everything I did on the XPS-15, including the setup for DBD, and it ran just terribly. It has something to do with the Nvidia drivers not playing well with Fedora. The GPU is an RTX 2060, but that&rsquo;s way better than an integrated graphics driver on a laptop, or so I thought. Launching DBD took forever. I tried several YouTube videos and tutorials explaining how to install the drivers on Fedora, but each attempt ended worse than the one before it. I ended up throwing in the towel and rolling the dice with a Debian distribution, Pop OS! Surprisingly, it worked like a charm, if a charm didn&rsquo;t need Secure Boot enabled. I&rsquo;m at peace with it. DBD runs smooth and fast like I am used to. So now I have Pop OS on the tower, Fedora on the Dell XPS laptop, and I put Windows 11 on the spare laptop if I need to do any FiveM testing.</p>
<p>Dead by Daylight just put out some Developer notes concerning the upcoming patch. They are nerfing the &ldquo;Eruption&rdquo; killer perk, and buffing the &ldquo;Any Means Necessary&rdquo; perk. They plan to improve their custom-game AI bots, and also eliminate someone getting the same map twice in-a-row unless someone brings a map offering. The community seems to be reacting well to the announced future changes. Honestly, it&rsquo;s just nice to see that the devs are listening, regardless of how folks feel about a specific change, they are listening. There was also a teaser trailer for the next chapter. People are already speculating that we&rsquo;re getting the Terminator as a new killer, but I seriously doubt that. The intellectual property behind that license is so large that we would have heard about it by now. Regardless of who or what the new chapter is, I&rsquo;m excited for it!</p>
<p>Changing subjects, we just watched the second episode of MTV&rsquo;s The Challenge Season 38 Finale (yes the finale is at least 3 episodes long). I have to be honest, while this is undeniably the longest final they&rsquo;ve ever done (&ldquo;100 hrs&rdquo;), it doesn&rsquo;t feel like the hardest final they&rsquo;ve ever done. I don&rsquo;t know if something is getting lost in editing, or if the first 4 hours being traveling left a sour taste in my mouth. It&rsquo;s clearly a difficult endeavor, but honestly previous seasons feel like they were more intense. They&rsquo;ve had 2 eating challenges already, so I know it&rsquo;s tough as I am a notoriously picky eater, but they are letting them sleep at night. I wonder if they adjusted things because certain contestants got injured and had to leave mid-finale. I&rsquo;m just not excited or rooting for anyone, which is never what you want when you&rsquo;re indulging in reality competition shows.</p>
<p>Netflix dropped a new season (or at least new episodes) of their show &ldquo;You.&rdquo; I haven&rsquo;t had a chance to watch it yet, but that&rsquo;s the big thing in the queue this month along side HBO&rsquo;s &ldquo;The Last of Us.&rdquo; My wife also binged &ldquo;Friends from College,&rdquo; and after catching the last few episodes, I enjoyed a few laughs.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s all I have for today. The US shot down something over Alaska, Coronavirus is surging 3 years later, and Fedora doesn&rsquo;t jive with Nvidia. Hug those close to you work to live. Have a good weekend.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Remote Gameplay Sucks</title>
            <link>https://megasmidge.com/posts/remote-gameplay-sucks/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 22:25:16 -0800</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://megasmidge.com/posts/remote-gameplay-sucks/</guid>
            <description>Well I had a plan, but things didn&amp;rsquo;t go quite how I expected. RDP was just way too rough to play Dead By Daylight. Luckily, Steam made a tool called Steam Link that you can install on a linux machine or mobile device. It allows you to run the games from your main computer, and see the games on your remote computer. You send your keyboard/mouse from the remote computer to the main computer to play the game.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well I had a plan, but things  didn&rsquo;t go quite how I expected. RDP was just way too rough to play Dead By Daylight. Luckily, Steam made a tool called Steam Link that you can install on a linux machine or mobile device. It allows you to run the games from your main computer, and see the games on your remote computer. You send your keyboard/mouse from the remote computer to the main computer to play the game. The big issue here is tiny amounts of latency, which in DBD matters for skill checks. It&rsquo;s possible to get a sense of the delay, and adjust for it, and I think with practice it would be doable, especially for a casual survivor. Playing killer was more enjoyable.  It was tough with all the dark maps rendering light quickly enough, but it was a better experience than survivor. If I&rsquo;m being honest with myself, I&rsquo;m not going to play the game this way. I just get too competitive to play with a sub-par experience. For the time being, I&rsquo;m going to attempt to follow youtuber G0rillaBiscuit&rsquo;s guide to installing DBD on Linux, and try to run it locally without the fancy GPU&hellip;.. which sort of makes me wonder if I should just put Fedora on the tower.</p>
<p>Anyways, DBD wasn&rsquo;t the only game on my radar. I wanted to help my friend test the blackjack script he&rsquo;s been developing for FiveM. All of the existing FiveM scripts we&rsquo;ve seen do not allow for splitting, and it&rsquo;s unclear if it&rsquo;s a true shoe/deck to be played through versus pure random-number-generator for every card pull. I tried doing via Chrome Remote Desktop, RDP, I even tried that Steam Link thing from above, but none of them could get me something smooth enough to event sit down at the blackjack table. I ended up pulling out another keyboard, mouse, and monitor, and just running both Fedora and Windows machines side by side for the day. I guess that&rsquo;s another reason I can&rsquo;t put Fedora on the tower.</p>
<p>I didn&rsquo;t get anything done today on the &ldquo;hack the box&rdquo; site I&rsquo;ve been toying around with, but I did run into a WINDOWS problem where I needed to download a certificate file (.cer) that was blocked by security download settings. Normally I would get around this by changing the file extension to .txt but that didn&rsquo;t work for some reason. Luckily, when it would ask me to provide a file name, I would leave that window open, and and open another file explorer, and find a temporary.crdownload stand in file waiting for me to name / the file to finish downloading, and I was able to open that temporary file with notepad. I could then take the contents of that, and copy paste it into another notepad, and save that as a .cer file.</p>
<p>Final notes before I head off to bed, I saw a video about Vanilla OS which allows you to use dnf and aur and apt in separate containers all on the same machine. Looks pretty interesting!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Setting Windows Aside</title>
            <link>https://megasmidge.com/posts/setting-windows-aside/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 19:31:43 -0800</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://megasmidge.com/posts/setting-windows-aside/</guid>
            <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a Windows user most of my 34 years on this earth. It was a matter of what my parents had in the house growing up in the 90s. As someone who got into videogames at a young age, Windows was the only way to go at the time. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t interested in building anything or being super technical, and it never even crossed my mind that I could be &amp;ldquo;good at computers&amp;rdquo; to pay the bills.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been a Windows user most of my 34 years on this earth. It was a matter of what my parents had in the house growing up in the 90s. As someone who got into videogames at a young age, Windows was the only way to go at the time. I wasn&rsquo;t interested in building anything or being super technical, and it never even crossed my mind that I could be &ldquo;good at computers&rdquo; to pay the bills. After graduating with a severely impractical Bachelor&rsquo;s in Religious Studies, and then bouncing around jobs and industries for 5 years, I landed in IT, and 5 years after that, I moved into Cybersecurity, namely administrating a major Splunk instance, their SIEM product, and their SOAR product.</p>
<p>It was this career move that exposed me to Linux, as Red Hat pretty much powers everything in the real world. Around the same time, I finally got around to watching the show Mr. Robot. That&rsquo;s a topic for another time, but the point is that it was another thing pushing me down the Cybersecurity rabbit hole. Things like Trinity running nmap in the Matrix that I never noticed or understand before, began to jump out at me left and right. I still feel like quite a novice in the linux world, but I have played around enough to know that right now I love Fedora and Gnome. Maybe one day I&rsquo;ll slap together the patience to get Arch up and running with something like KDE, but that is not this day.</p>
<p>In the recent years, my Windows usage at home has been to play games like GTA-RP via FiveM, The Red Dead 2 equivalent, RedM, the spaghetti code battle royale PUBG: Battlegrounds, the super old Star Wars MMORPG &ldquo;Star Wars Galaxies&rdquo; via private servers on SWGEMU, and finally, the asynchronous horror game Dead By Daylight.Some of those work natively on Linux, some work with some tweaks, and others do not work at all. Especially spaghetti code. After 1200 hours in Dead By Daylight (DBD), I don&rsquo;t want to say I&rsquo;m done, but it&rsquo;s not a relaxing pastime. I get competitive with it, which is fine, but it&rsquo;s not recharging or replenishing me. It&rsquo;s not helping me unwind from the day or de-stress in anyway. I don&rsquo;t find myself wanting to stream it.</p>
<p>Am I ever gonna get to the point? Jesus. Currently I&rsquo;m excited about a bunch of things in the tech space. The main thing holding me back from having my office desk just linux was gaming. DBD might, maybe, work with linux with some tweaking, but I don&rsquo;t feel like figuring that out right now. I&rsquo;m also interested in testing some FiveM (GTA) scripts that my friends are developing for Blackjack, another hobby I&rsquo;d like to discuss at another time.</p>
<p><em>Sellout warning, this paragraph has  paid links to Amazon that you can support me with</em>
So, I think I&rsquo;ve come to a compromise of sorts. In the mid-late 2022 timeframe, I splurged on a <a href="https://amzn.to/3HDbnIX">Dell XPS-15 laptop</a>, and I specifically got one with integrated graphics, not a fancy GPU for gaming/streaming because I want to use it for development and tech work. I&rsquo;m punching this up on it right now (in VIM of all things, I know)! I also got a docking station so I could hook this thing up on my desk to the monitors/keyboard/etc. The final thing I needed it to work with was my <a href="https://amzn.to/3lgpmgr">TC Helicon GOXLR-mini</a>, which is an external usb device that does a lot of fancy cool things but the most important is take in my <a href="https://amzn.to/3JMyrbc">Shure SM7B</a> microphone. I love that microphone but it seems very silly considering no one sees it anymore because I haven&rsquo;t been streaming. I said &ldquo;sees&rdquo; it not &ldquo;hears&rdquo; it because I do still use discord on the laptop, and to be honest, you can sound just as good on discord with exteremely cheap usb microphones.</p>
<p>So what&rsquo;s the compromise? I could have installed Fedora on the existing gaming tower with the fancy GPU that I&rsquo;ve been using, and I have tried that before, but I just can&rsquo;t bring myself to say goodbye to DBD and FiveM forever. So. The plan is to have the laptop docked as the main setup for everything, and to have the tower just plugged into power and network (no keyboard, mouse, or monitors). If I want to access the Windows tower, I will RDP (remote) into the tower from my linux laptop and use it that way.</p>
<p>That&rsquo;s the plan. I&rsquo;m not sure if it will totally work or not, but I at least want to try it!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>First</title>
            <link>https://megasmidge.com/posts/first/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 17:08:40 -0800</pubDate>
            
            <guid>https://megasmidge.com/posts/first/</guid>
            <description>Just testing to make sure this works.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Just testing to make sure this works.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
